We stopped at number 332, right
?  Who is the
woman in line 332 talking to
?
Oh, ignorance, misunderstanding
.  It's a misunderstanding, and she's
talking to that
misunderstanding.  I heard that some of
you have finished an image,
right?  And I heard that
we're going to have a performance
tomorrow, right?  from each house and I
listened to it, it was very good
and I will make the judges listen
tomorrow.  She called him very
arrogant and said, "You think you're a
master, but you're not really a
master."  You lack everything, you lack those
things, okay, you lack
good qualities, you don't have the things that
bring you, you have qualities
like meditation.  Okay, I'll start
with point 332. In point
332, you said that nothing
depends on anything and
you said that everything is
unchanging.  You
said that they were
hard teeth.
Does the bad part of your mind
think that nothing
will ever change?  Is there a way that is
n't a direct way?  Okay.  Someone
has a very good question.  Okay.   Of course, of
course you understand things
change, but you're craving it, but
you'll be hungry after lunch, and I
think you'll sit there in
long classes, and you'll be even hungrier,
and but your hunger
changes.  No one can say that things do
n't change; the way things are
expressed, it doesn't say that things
don't change, and he didn't say
that.  And who is she blaming it on?
Why would I change it for him again?
My teacher in the G course said that if
someone gives you all the
questions and answers, does that mean
they will give you all the
answers to your questions
?
Okay, listen.  If things don't come from
your seeds, if things
don't come from your seeds,
they will never change.
In your mind
, you think that everything comes from
outside, not from
within.
100 dollars for Tibetan, not
W. In this country, you
can win all the votes, but
you won't be
president.  Is that Donzin?  The
person who thinks everything comes
from
this side isn't
everything; he's not my student
.  Okay.
In means something is coming
from the object
to my eye. Trans means the
way you see things, and
what does ERA mean?  Then it means that the person
who has directly touched the world of diamonds
and means seeing
the indirectness and son means the
opposite son means son means
not a not a and the
world is coming from not coming from
this side they don't understand the world is coming
from
this side and it will lead me to a
next question.  Are you ready?  This is a
very easy money problem.  So,
if your family asks why you're
taking a week to come to the hospital, you can
say, "I come here to earn a lot of
money, and that's my job,
okay?"  Are you ready for this question
?  How
many times is the diamond mentioned in the Diamond Sutra
?
Raise your hand,
zero, even
$100 for everything,
everything
I'm trying to say
is, you've been the manager of this place
for 12 years, and you can answer, uh,
two more questions for money,
and what is the Sanskrit word for diamond
?  What is diamond?  Vra,
the Sanskrit word for diamond, means "
va," which signifies strength.  It means
power.  Vra means power.   Okay
.  That means vegetable.
Vegetables.  Old vegetables.  Okay.  Why
in that ancient era?  Okay.  And they
agreed with my wife that they said
the old vegetables made you
stronger.  Old vegetables will make you
stronger, and they believe that staying in that
ancient way is important.  But not now
, not in this day and age.  Okay
?  Whenever you
see diamonds, whenever you
hear someone talking about diamonds...  And
the question is, are people talking
about diamonds?  It's not that
the Diamond person is
very suspicious, okay, it
means they're sending you some kind of
message. Someone asked you why
they call it the Diamond Sutra, and
you said it's a thing,
it's a communication, right? That
's the Diamond Path. Why do
diamonds and the Diamond Sutra have anything
to do with diamonds?
And if you're in the Diamond Path, of
course, there are some messages
here.  Okay, anyway
.  If someone gave it to me, I
don't know, but it's too much
.  Okay.  Now let's
answer the question without any money
.  She blamed the devil for
his belief that nothing had
changed.  He believed what she said, and she
said, "You believe that nothing
changes."  Why did she say
that?  Okay.  Speak into the microphone for
your teacher, not for money.
Can I answer
?  There were a few people who had to pay
their teacher $100 in order to get an answer to their
question.  Okay.  Don't forget the question!
Why did the angel blame the devil for
this misunderstanding?
Why did she tell him that
you think nothing has changed?  Of
course he didn't think that,
and you and I have lived for
many years without ever touching the
world of diamonds.
Why do you believe that nothing changes
and we can see
everything changing every moment,
and she is blaming you for being
wrong about it in a very extreme way
and from an extreme point of view, and you
think that individual existence
comes from itself and the result is the
belief that things don't change,
so if he says that everything
above and you believe that everything
is coming from this side, and if I
ask you if you believe that they have
n't changed, and of course
not, and if you think that everything
changes without the
existence itself, it can't change, if it can't change, then it never
changes, it can't change because if
it doesn't come from
your seed, why does it change?
Because your seed changes. And when
your seed, when the
seed creates the tree, why does it
create a tree?  The seed is gone,
but the seed measured an
energy for the plant, and that energy
created the plant. Then the
plant will use that energy to
grow, and then the plant will die,
right?  But if everything comes from the
seed and they do
n't exist forever,
they die because they didn't come
from your seed.  Why do
they change?  But if they
came from this side, okay, and everything that
created them changed, and why would she
blame him, and that person said
nothing changed, and like
that, I would never say that.  But
if you think
that if he's blaming the
lack of any friends,
he's blaming her—no,
not a friend,
but
someone who's very lonely.  He's
blaming her for everything not going
home and home and here in the mind
of a person you will never be
able to be present you
again if when you
are in the middle of class and I
think about nothing and then the part of your
time worrying about those
people who are bothering me is like what
and he has blamed her to
become a very lonely person and she
has no friends
she doesn't even go home
to her husband anymore.  And why did she
say that?  It's not me
without any friends; it's you
without me.  Why?  Because all the
friends
you think you have do
n't even exist, but next time
you might have a fight with
your husband and friends.  You can
try that.  Okay.  And that might
confuse you.  If things
don't start from your side.  They
cannot survive.  First, they cannot be
changed.  Secondly, they don't
exist anyway.  Okay?  And
can the two husbands be in the kitchen?  The
husband who is hurting you
even though you haven't done
much, not even a little bit
.  I didn't do anything, I didn't do anything at all
.  Okay.  He's very good at that.
I didn't do anything.  I didn't do anything
.  I think he used it
at home, right?
[Music]
Okay.  And the wife said that my husband was just
yelling at me.
But I didn't do anything.  But
in this system, if the pen comes
from you, then the husband must
come from you.  Okay.  The husband
is saying whatever you want, it has to
come from you.  Do you understand?  And then
you, and if you understand that
it's coming from you, you
can change it. If you don't understand, and
he will be lost forever, he will exist forever, and
he will not exist, and
that thing will exist forever and not
exist.  And he told her that she
didn't have any friends at all.  And
she said that I am a friend to
everyone.  I am a friend to everyone.
Don't tell me I don't have any
friends
.  Everyone in this world
is my friend.  Okay.  I've been
having very good relationships with everyone.  And who
is speaking?  An angel who
understands that the seed is coming from
your side.  I understand, I love everyone
and they love me because I am real and
because I am down to the seed.  Okay
?  And I have a real relationship
that comes from a seed.  And when you've
entered a relationship and you've
nurtured it
and honored all the
other people's appreciation for that relationship, right?
And I didn't have any luck with my husband, I
didn't have any luck with my husband,
and I honor the relationship,
and I keep my promise, and
I have forced him to keep it.
So I have a grudge against
everyone.  And that means if
you understand that everything
comes from the seed, then you can
get close to everything because it is the
truth, it is a real world.  It is just the
real world.  And what
if everything comes
from the seed?  If you do
n't understand that you're living in a
place that isn't real, then you're living
in a place that doesn't exist.
And then you're basically the team that's
crazy.  That means all 8 billion
people are completely insane.  Okay.  But,
but, or they are, they are, they
are the Buddhas, but I didn't
say, I didn't say that they are
.  Next, she's in the
mood for a friendship, okay?  She
has this
idea that, naturally,
people are close to me
because they depend on me.  They
depend on me.  Okay.  How does
the world depend on me?  My seed tray
.  My seeds.  The
world depends
on me.  Don't tell me I don't have
any friends.  The first time, and the
next time, if your husband says, "
No, don't tell me you do
n't have any friends, but I have
many friends. Everything depends on
me because my mind is creating
everything, okay?"  Okay.  I think this
is the $100 question, and everyone's
starting to think like this.  Okay, let's get ready,
everyone.
He said that you are a lonely person,
you are a failure, you don't have
any friends, you
were there once a year when you
went to Donghuang Mountain, it only took 5
minutes.  And okay.  And he
accused her, and she said, "
No, no, I'm a friend to
everyone."  And he asked why,
how, and she said that everyone is
my friend because they're coming from me,
okay?  The pen, the pen, and everything else came from
me.  So they like
me.  They are my friends.  They are my friends
.  Okay?  It's called
dependence.  It's called
dependency.  But there's a deeper idea
here.  Would you like to delve
deeper into the idea here?  If it's a matter of
interdependence, okay, I'll make
it
simpler.  The pen you use depends on the seed
you plant.  Do you want it to be super simple
or roughly simple?  Okay, it's
pretty simple, right?
The pen you use depends on your seed
.  Therefore, the pen is your friend.  Okay.   Okay
.  Okay.  Sorry.  You are a friend of the pen.
You are a friend of the pen.  Because if you were
n't there, that friend wouldn't be
able to be there.
Do you understand?  But that guy is also
your friend.  The pen is also your friend
.
The interdependence is
not cause and
effect.  It is interdependence.   Okay
.  The tree depends on the seed.   Okay
.  Let me make it simpler.  The tree
depends on the seed, and the seed
depends on the tree.  So how can I make
the tree reach deep into the
$100 seed?
Your seed creates the
image of the tree and the seed.  Then
you are the seed within it, and you
are a mental image that relates
to it as a
cause and effect.  Okay.  Okay?  The
seed clearly produces the tree,
but what if
the tree also produces seeds? Because you
can't say
your seed produces the
pen, but your pen also
produces seeds,
right?  Your seed creates the
pen, but the pen created the
seed of the seed; it
is truly the root of
true dependence.  Okay.  A way of getting along that
everyone can.  Like this,
everyone's doing this, okay, I'm doing it, I'm creating a
pen, but that pen also
creates your seed
because they can't be
seeds until they're created
into something.  Do you understand?  Diamonds are
abundant, diamond mountains exist, and
everyone
knows the
secret of ordinary DCI students.
Everything comes from a seed, everything
originates from a seed.   The
surplus diamonds of the master diamond mountain
.  Everything came from the seed of the plant, the
pen came from
my side.  The pen came from my seed
.  Buy
fresh sourdough.  Okay.  I created the seed, I made the
pen.  The pen comes from my seed side
.  And my seed was
also created because of the pen, you know
.  It is called the origin of
dependence.  It is, it is two-way.  It
's two-dimensional and it's much deeper, but
we don't usually teach it.  Okay.
People don't usually teach it, but
it's true.  Okay.  $500, even including
WM
[music]
.  What ancient wisdom would give rise to
something where the seed is that seed?
The ancient example that gives about
the seed,
the pot,
the ok, the three spheres, the
sphere shape, the three spheres
merging together, the spear.   Okay
.  In the ancient language it was
called, uh, it was called spears,
sorry, it was called
spears, it was, in the ancient text it was
called, yes, it was spears, and they
had something, something, a spearhead,
and they had metal at the tip,
and there was even a debate
throughout this ancient battle of wits,
and they ran around
their campsite, and they started a fire, and they
started cooking something, and they always,
but they had, they were
very good fighters, and they put the
spears on the ground because
they could make
three-legged spears, three-
legged spears, and they depended on each other, they supported each
other to stand firm, okay,
they supported each other, and that's the
example.  That's just an example.  What is the example?
The pen depends on the seed,
and the seed depends on the
pen.  It is, it is, it is a
reciprocal relationship.  It's a reciprocal relationship
.  The husband comes from you,
but you also come from
your husband.  Because there would be no you
without the husband who comes from
you.  Okay?
And by the way, if you have a
problem with
someone, you're complicating the
relationship, and something is going on,
and one way, and one way, and it's clearly a
problem if you think that person is
n't coming from you. You also have to understand
that you're coming from them, and if you're
always blaming them, you're messing
things up.  But
what are you really thinking?  It is, it is two-way.
It's two-dimensional; it's really the tree
because the tree is defining the
seed.  If the person you're
in a relationship with is acting completely ridiculous, does
that prove you're ridiculous
?  It is very difficult.  That's
another difficulty.  It's also a
difficult thing.  If someone says you
're a jerk and you don't even think
it's coming from you and because it
reflects you.  Okay.  And they are defining
you, you know, they are defining
you,
okay?
And everyone is saying, "Oh, I
want to learn the Kim Can Thea school, teacher, but
I don't want to learn
philosophy, I only want to learn Kim Can Thea
."  I've been studying film for
12 years now.  I just want the extra gold.
I just gave you guys the extra diamonds
.  Do you understand?
Do you understand?  Okay.  All that she's
arguing about, all that's
happening here, is that you have to be in a
state of mind for an argument, and
that's the goal of this whole book
.  And the angel was arguing
with the devil, and he said, "
You're the loser."  And you go,
you go home and live alone.  You
come here and then you only go home once a year
.  Oh, and
I'm okay, you're very,
very lonely.  I am not alone.
I am a friend to everyone who
lives on this planet.  Because
they are the seeds, they are the white tree, and we
are the seeds.  They created me, who I am
.  They created me, and it's very
deep.  Okay.  If you guys go back to
DCI, if you're a
seed person, okay, that pen creates seeds,
seeds.  Okay, thanks for the pen.
Thank you for the pen.
Thank.  If I hadn't given
you the seeds, I wouldn't be here.  And if
you have to say, "But
without you, I wouldn't be here," then I would
n't be able to be a seed.  Do you understand
?  The dependence, the
dependence, the dependence—it's really a
two-way street.  It's a two-
way street, meaning she'll
never be lonely, she'll never be
alone.
And if you understand
interdependence, you are truly
profound friends to everyone in
this world and on every other planet.
But I don't want to blow your heads off
.  Then I'll say it again, if you
truly understand that
you are you, you are
automatically connected to everyone on this planet.  And if
you understand the saying, "Understand the pen," then
everyone on this planet is your friend.
Everyone, absolutely everyone, is
interdependent.  Okay.  And don't tell
me you're calling that loneliness.
Because you only perform
here once a year.  But all of it,
but all day long, me and everyone
else.  Who is he?
He is, he is ignorance,
ignorance, misunderstanding.  Missing out on a
misunderstanding
.  And she made it into the very
alluring part of the very alluring list
.  She said that she had
boasted that you were the one who would
win.  That ignorance, you are lonely, and
I am sitting here with you, and him,
so many friends, you even, okay, what
kind of person is he? Okay, please, please tell me,
who is she? She started, this is
the list of my friends, and
she started going into the
list, the going, the appearance of the
sun and
moon, are my friends, whether they exist
or not, and the
directions, and my body, east, west, and
they depend on me.  Do you understand
?  She's bragging, she
's boasting about how many
friends he has.  He's accusing
her of having fewer friends, but
she's like that because she's a loser,
and she's like, "okay," but that's not the case at all
.  I have friends who
are in very high positions
.  The sun, the moon, the east
, and the west.  I have eastern
and western feces.  I have day and
night.  I have day and night.  They are
my friends.  Do you understand
?  And summer, winter, autumn, spring, spring
, summer, autumn, winter—my uncle is also
my friend
.  I'm not kidding, I'm not joking
.  The fact that when the rain
falls, the fact that when the flowers bloom,
when the fruit ripens, and
they come from me, and she is
boasting about how many friends
she has.  She said that I have
everyone.  Okay.  Stanley $100.   He wo
n't answer anyway
.  This is a discussion about the
boundary she's really talking about
, the boundary between day and
night.  My friend is and is the boundary between
east and west.  My friend is the boundary
between winter and summer.  And
what is inside this ancient celestial realm
?  Shima Shima,
okay, but I... I didn't... did I tell
you it was 50 dollars
?  What is the Tibetan word for Shima
?  In Tibetan, Shima means ginseng.
Please name the ginseng
.  Okay.  There are two words you should
learn.  You should learn Tibetan. The
Tibetan language is some ts am
tsam.  And the Sanskrit word is sima.  Sima
means boundary or
border.  When they sew those shirts,
when they put these threads together,
it's called sim.  It's called a SIM card.  It comes
from the ancient Sanskrit word and sim.  And the
word "scripture" also comes from
that word.  Okay.  What does sima
mean
?  And sima means to
form a boundary, a
border line, and it's very important for the
center of reach because it's a
big, very important thing
for the center of reach.  Because
every time we do
that retreat, a quiet, peaceful retreat
, a serious retreat,
we have to create a boundary,
a line, and we have to
make a boundary between
those two boundaries.  Okay.  And those two boundaries,
at least two boundaries.  At least two
boundaries.  Okay.  Okay.  You have someone run
up that mountain to put a tree down
and or you can
put a piece of paper on the door
of your cabin and it's a
smaller circle.
But this is the SIM card you were
talking about.  Okay.  You guys
extend the letter 'a'
and it means
boundary.  And I told everyone in
Donghuang that when I was doing three
three-year retreats, El said remember that I was
in the car and I
finished the Diamond Cutting book
in the car and the
last page so that I could go into the
reset gate and I said stop and
start so that I could quickly finish
that book and I gave her the
table to give to the publisher
and then I went in, we parked the car
and I went in through the
gate and it
was a cowshed gate and
when I took the gate, it was
closed and I said that I would
not leave this gate for
three years.  It was a
very strange feeling.  Those of you who have done a
three-year retreat know
this feeling. Three years, and you're
okay with it? I won't leave
this boundary for three years.   Okay
.
While I was in Donghuang, I lost a
tooth.  I lost a tooth between
different retreats and I
said I had to go into town,
I had to go to the
dentist.  Okay.  And then someone said, "Okay, do you have
any glue to stick it back together
?"  But the tooth has already fallen out.
I don't know what to do.  But I
did, we were going to put it back together, we were going to glue
it back together with super, super, super glue,
but I didn't break
that thing and I didn't go out of
that place for 3 years, 3 months, and 3
days.  And the idea here is that the
angel is speaking to the great man right here.
Shima, but
and si ma here means the line
between the sun and the moon, the
boundary between the seed and the pen, and
this is the boundary between east and
west.  Okay, we have a project
in Mexico, on the other side of the border, in the
city of DAS.
We tried to type the
sounds down, but
the computers were
gone, but we really
did it, we really did it.   Okay
.  I said I had to go for the dollars,
I had to do something, and I
crossed that border and spoke to
those workers.  And I told the
police
that, and is there anything I can do
?  And he said something to me, but
they don't trust you for
anything.  And
I, okay, and I
could perhaps put one foot on the American border, could
n't I?  Is it on the Mexican border?  And I
want to know how easy it feels, and I'm
like, I don't know
anymore.  And I looked straight at the
border.  I looked straight at the border,
and do you know what?  They feel the same
.  I don't feel anything at all
.  I don't have any boundaries; I
don't feel any sense of
boundaries at all.  One foot is in America and the other is
in
Mexico, I can't
see.  But there is a certain reputation associated with this
profession.  Do you understand?  People on the other side are being
different.
And s 6 min 6 min 6 about 2 m á 2 m
way people have too much food and
they are dying because of too much weight because of
something, they are
gaining too
much weight.  Do you think a
politician made the
border line?  No, that's not it.
Your seeds create
those borders.  And she said that it is the
border of borders, and that it is my friend
.  The boundary between you and
others, the boundary
between the eye and the pen, the
boundary between you and me.  All of
this comes from the female seed, and the border is
also coming from the seed, understand?
The evil is coming from the seed, understand?
And she didn't say, "Okay, the
sun and moon come from me, the
east and west come from me, day and night
come from me, okay, summer, autumn, winter, spring,
autumn, winter come from me," but
she didn't say, "You created
that boundary, you created
that mind."  But if
people understood that, a
strange new language would develop.  David and I
went to Donghuang so that
David could translate for me and for the
Chinese people
.  I understand you need to change
your language
.  All human language
is based on misunderstanding.  The words "you"
and "I" are both incorrect.
And if you're a good person, you
think, "Because I'm like this, it's not
real,
it shouldn't be me, it shouldn't be
you."  We should either have lunch or
we shouldn't have lunch, but the
problem is there's a
fine line.  Is that right?  I am you and you
are me.  So if you understand
this, then the partner in
your mind is telling you that you don't have any
friends.  Okay.  You don't
understand.  Okay.  I am a friend to
everyone.  And the person and the
angel said that you are a loser,
you are a lonely person.  You are the kind of
person who has no friends and you
don't realize that you can't
exist without other people.
Do you understand?  It is very powerful, it is very
strong.  It is very powerful.  That's why
it took us 10 years to get to
this point.  And we have
completed a poem, we have finished a
poem, we have done with a poem with a
verse.  And when you think about
your friends saying, 'Okay, you
understand the seed, you understand the pen,'
okay, and you have friends, and you
don't even know who those friends are,
but you really have
good friends because they are me.  They are me.  Don't
tell me I don't have any friends
.  The truth is, I don't have
friends because I am who
my friends are, and they are who I am.  And that's why, that
's how it gets closer to you.  And if
you understand this, your life
will become truly wonderful.  And
your life will be incredibly joyful every day
.  Realize that you are everyone
else,
and it will be so much fun all day long, and
that fun will never stop,
right?
And they talked very cheerfully.  It was a lot of fun.
I mean,
I don't even care about those philosophical things
.  If you experience
joy all day, every single day, that is
happiness, and that is true happiness.  And
you guys just have fun, either on
your birthday or something
like that, it's only once a
year.  But if there's any
profound wisdom here, someone asked
me how many students I
wanted, and I said about
365 birthdays, and my wife said
we weren't eating in the desert, but
someone had a birthday and I
had to eat it, okay? And the boundary comes from
you, and the boundary is also coming from you, and
maybe they're not really
helpful. And they're related, they're
directly related to the retreat
because the word for retreat, in the ancient language,
quima in
Sanskrit and Sam in Tibetan, it's
boundary, and it means to stay within
this boundary, and it's
another one, another boundary, and it
means to be silent. Sometimes you think
you can think more clearly if you're
not around 100 people.
It's all around people, it's so
sweet, but sometimes
you need to be alone in your
house, in your cabin, and it's
really
great.  And when you guys go out, I don't
know, if I didn't know John Ry,
but I had this thing, when
I remember looking out the door, and
I remember looking out the
door and saying it wasn't
fun, and just sitting there for 1000 days and saying I did
n't have a toilet, I didn't have
drinking water, I didn't have
electricity, I was in the desert, but I, but
I mean, it wasn't fun,
and I was thinking why. Because
nobody was there, nobody was helping,
nobody was helping, and
I couldn't have the fun of
helping others, and I
felt lonely, and I thought that
retreat was really cool,
but I didn't have the chance to
make an evening for anyone,
and I didn't have the chance to
talk to anyone.  I don't have time to
talk to anyone.  I have the opportunity to
serve people.  And I think one
of the reasons I go into a
retreat is that you're having
a four-day retreat where you're
quiet and you start to
miss everyone else.  And on the first day,
you guys thought it was great, but in the
end, you had no one to talk to
.  And by the third day, oh my god,
I was already starting to miss him.  And
there are three things you have felt lonely about, and
during that time,
during that period, think about,
think about the Bodhisattva, think about what it means to
become a Bodhisattva.  When you've been
in a retreat long enough,
alone, you'll understand how much you need people,
how much you need other people, and how sweet it is to have
others to
serve.  And it's not a
matter of whether you have bad people or
good people; serving bad people
is more enjoyable than serving
good people.  It is an art form.  It's
a form of art, a
high form of art.  Do you understand?  Alright
.  And she's leaving tonight,
how much time do we have left?
And she went in and she went into the
darkness and a little dark here a little
gloomy here and she even and
she and suddenly she went
into another place.  Okay, we're still
on stanza 337, guys.  In stanza
337, she says there is a boundary
between Spring, Summer, Autumn, and Winter.  Okay, okay, okay.  That's
fine.  And she said there's a
boundary called life and death and
she started to get dark and
it was like
this girl was like there was
a
boundary between life and death, life and
death.  And we say that there is a
distinction you can be sick or
you can have a surge of energy
and you can suffer on the
diamond mountain for a week and from a heat and a
week and a cold, a
constant heat and a constant cold,
even your toilet seat
.  Okay.  And the okay and hunger are different
in one thing and different on one
hand and everything else and she even
suddenly she crosses
another boundary between pain and
suffering between getting old and dying and she
will go into the four higher truths, the four
truths of a and that is the four truths of
suffering and she says that I created those
boundaries between those four
truths I created the mind between
suffering and the cause of
suffering and I created the
boundary between nirvana and the creation of
a path and I created
those boundaries and I created
the boundary you did that
okay and between life and
death if you understand that the
boundaries are coming from you you
can change them and if you
don't understand they are coming from you then you
can't change them or
if you understand where,
where this boundary comes from,
you can change  Can we change that boundary between
life and death?
The tant course, the tant class.  Okay,
I'm going to talk about what I want to
say about what I've been working on and what I'm currently doing on a
particular project.  You know how to help
people, to assist another person
in the second part of
their life.  And we developed
an
idea, and I'm teaching something like
that.  DDU?  Give it to
DSDU.  And someone told
me.  Okay, so you're teaching the
second part of life, right?  No, I said
I'm not teaching what I already have; I'm teaching the
beginning part, and what comes next will
follow.  I have no interest in teaching about
you old people and you people
with kidney disease and you people who die.  I do not
know.  I'm teaching you about
the second part of your life and
what happens after that.
How can you have a transition?
How can you
transition
peacefully and not forget
that it's okay?
That's just the first part.
Just the first half, and the
second half will
happen later, okay?  And when you
start a project when you're 40, that's
the first part of your life.
And we have to become
masters of the second part
of your life, and it will go
deep.  And don't think that
life, life as the beginning
and the depth of my life, just keep
thinking like that.  The second part of
your life is the first part of
your life, and then what
happens is you die.  And then you
need another half.  And if
you study well, and if you study
well about how to do retreat, and if
you study well at the diamond mountain, it will be very
fun, it will be really great.  Do you
know that the color of the sky is in
the deepest part of my life
?  That's the color of the peach bottle,
imagine you're
planning your next life, your
next teenage years, your next
adulthood, and imagine
you're planning them
now, and what I'm talking about...
and if you say I'm crazy, I do
n't even
care.  If you want to give me $100, I'm perfectly
fine with it.  It's impossible that I'm crazy,
maybe I know something.
But that happened, and we
have to decide whether he doesn't or he might
.  Okay.  I'm looking forward to
that.  I will see you all again.  M.